西元2026年  考古学家在内华达州沙漠
In the year 2026, archaeologists working in the Nevada desert...
发现一个通往火星古城的入口
discovered a portal to an ancient city on Mars.
这个入口被称为"方舟"
They called this portal the Ark.
二十年后  我们仍在试图解开
Twenty years later, we're still struggling to understand...
它的秘密
why it was built...
并了解制造它的文明
and what happened to the civilization that built it.
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视修正制作
最新最快的HR-HDTV 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
字幕：  guiling     后期：  guiling
联合航太公司  欧都瓦研究中心  火星
UNION AEROSPACE CORPORATION OLDUVAI RESEARCH FACILITY, MARS
柯博士
Dr. Carmack!
准许进入-柯博士
柯博士
Dr. Carmack!
欧都瓦研究中心柯博士  识别证号6627
This is Dr. Carmack, Classified Research, Olduvai, ID 6627.
发生第五级紧急状况
We've had a Level 5 breach.
立刻进行隔离程序
Implement quarantine procedures immediately.
立刻进行隔离
Implement quarantine procedures now.
毁灭战士
海军陆战队  特种部队总部
MARINE CORPS SPECIAL OPS RRTS HEADQUARTERS
美国加州二十九棕榈市
TWENTYNINE PALMS, CALIFORNIA, USA
我听得很清楚  将军
Reading you loud and clear, General.
联合航太要求我们帮忙
Union Aerospace has requested assistance to contain...
处理火星研究中心紧急状况
a Level 5 breach at their Olduvai facility.
有多少人需要救援
How many personnel involved?
六名科学家被困在
Six scientists are under lockdown in a high-security lab...
机密实验室
where the breach occurred.
研究中心则有79名员工
Another 79 UAC employees are on site.
-目前禁止进行方舟传送  -任务是什么
- Ark travel has been suspended. - What's the objective?
-最高机密  解除危险  -收到
- Code red. Assess level of threat. - Assess level of threat.
保护并取回联合航太财产
Protect and retrieve UAC property.
不择手段保持方舟隔离
Maintain quarantine at both Ark portals by any means necessary.
-使用极端手段  -极端手段
- Use extreme prejudice? - Extreme prejudice.
有必要的话  格杀勿论
If necessary, search and destroy. Over.
格杀勿论
Search and destroy.
收到命令  通话完毕
Orders received and understood. Out.
你想来硬的吗
Oh, you're trying to get nasty now, huh?
你死定了  逊脚
Now you dead. You dead, sucker. All right, all right.
你要召唤兄弟  是吧
You wanna bring your boys? You wanna bring your boys?
不是吧
I don't believe this.
我向天父忏悔
I confess to God the father.
-我要发飙了  -小心墙壁
- I need help. - The wall, man.
我不敢相信
I don't believe this shit.
好不容易休假
Six months without a weekend...
专机竟然迟到
the goddamned transporters are five minutes late.
谁要赔我这五分钟宝贵时间
And that's five minutes of R and R I ain't never gonna get back.
放轻松  咱们在度假
Hey, relax, baby. We're on vacation.
这游戏超猛的
Yo. This game's layered, man.
-色鬼  你要去哪里玩  -我要去找乐子
- Where you going, Portman? - I'm going down to El Honto...
带一瓶酒  住进饭店
and I'm gonna lock myself in a motel room...
跟三个人妖玩妖精打架
with a bottle of tequila and three she-boys.
你真是有够变态
You're sick, man.
-我受够你了  色鬼  -牧师要讲道了
- I'm sick of your filth, Portman. - He speaks.
你呢  去战区度假吗
What's it gonna be, Reaps? An armed conflict someplace quiet?
是啊  来场丛林战
Yeah, a little relaxing jungle warfare?
或许你哪儿也去不了
Or maybe you're just gonna stay right here.
利用时间做伏地挺身
Spending my time doing pushups.
弟兄们  听好
Listen up, men.
休假取消
Leave is canceled.
拜托  这太扯了
Oh, man. I just... I don't believe this shit.
-混帐  -公爵  你有意见吗
- Fuck! - Got a problem with that, Duke?
没有呀  我超爱工作
Me, Sarge? Hell, no, I love my job.
-队长  怎么回事  -有一项新任务
- What's up, Sarge? - We got us a game.
菜鸟
Kid!
你正式加入雷霆战略反应小队
Son, you're now in the Rapid Response Tactical Squad...
简称雷霆小队
the RRTS.
集合
Fall in.
这下没搞头了  害你空欢喜一场  很扫兴吧
All dressed up and nowhere to go, huh, Portman?
-菜鸟  别忘了带奶嘴  -闭嘴
- Kid, don't forget your rattle. - Shut up, Portman.
-约翰  这次你不能去  -什么
- Not this time, John. - What?
-我们应付得来  -你在糊弄我吧
- We can handle this one. - You're bullshitting me.
不是  我们要去欧都瓦
No, I'm not bullshitting. We're going to Olduvai.
欧都瓦
Olduvai?
-你去休假吧  -这是命令吗
- Take the leave. - Is that an order?
这是建议
It's a recommendation.
等我回来再见
See you when I get back.
-可以出发了  -收到
- Aircraft ready to load. - Copy that.
光阴如梭  假期一下就结束
Great vacation. Damn, they go quick.
好像根本就没离开
Almost like we've never been away.
雷霆小队准备好了
We're a go.
一切OK  可以起飞
All systems are green. Prepare for takeoff.
收到  队长
Okay, Sarge, roger.
雷霆小队身份确认
RRTS Special Ops clearance verified.
代号:黑霸
Handle ID: Destroyer.
-老爹回来了  -代号:迈克
- Daddy's home. - Handle ID: Mac.
代号:色鬼  代号:牧师
Handle ID: Portman. Handle ID: Goat.
代号:菜鸟
Handle ID: The Kid.
-"菜鸟"  -代号:公爵
- "The Kid"? - Handle ID: Duke.
就是我
Say my name, baby.
雷霆小队身份确认
RRTS Special Ops clearance verified.
代号:队长
Handle ID: Sarge.
我不敢相信要通过方舟
I can't believe we're going through the Ark.
安啦  你一定会很爽
Don't worry, Kid. You're gonna love it.
-准备好了吗  -是  长官
- All set? - Yes, sir.
雷霆小队身份确认  代号:死神
RRTS Special Ops clearance verified. Handle ID: Reaper.
-升空  -空中六号升空
- Take us up! - RRTS air 6, airborne and en route.
菜鸟  你知道吗
You know, Kid, it's funny.
我前几天才向队长要求来只弱鸡
A couple of days ago I asked Sarge for a little pussy.
今天他就把你带进队里来
The next day he brought you onto the team.
色鬼  别找藉口
Don't give me an excuse, Portman.
没人会想你的
No one here will miss you.
大家看这里
Men, look in.
这是我们得到的资料
This is what we got from Simcon.
欧都瓦研究中心出了状况
We have a quarantine situation on Olduvai.
只要研究小组
They sent this message...
失去联系  他们就发出这则讯息
when the research team stopped responding to all communications.
欧都瓦
Olduvai.
欧度瓦研究中心柯博士  识别证号6627
This is Dr. Carmack, Classified Research, Olduvai, ID 6627.
发生第五级紧急状况
We've had a Level 5 breach.
立刻进行隔离程序
Implement quarantine procedures immediately.
重复
I repeat.
欧度瓦研究中心柯博士  识别证号6627
This is Dr. Carmack, Classified Research, Olduvai, ID 6627.
发生第五级紧急状况
We've had a Level 5 breach.
立刻进行隔离程序
Implement quarantine procedures now.
联合航太公司封锁了实验室
UAC have shut down the lab, men.
我们要过去找他们
We need to go up there, locate the team...
解除危险并确保研究中心的安全
eliminate the threat and secure the facility.
什么危险
What threat?
如果有东西想杀你  那就是危险
It goes like this, see: If it's trying to kill you, it's a threat.
救援小组出发
Rescue mission heading 147 degrees. Location Lima, Zulu, Foxtrot 14.
收到  通话完毕
Roger, Q-06. Badger 39 out.
收到
Copy, Badger 39.
-有多久了  -十年
- How long has it been? - Ten years.
你确定她还在那儿
Sure she's even still up there?
确定
Yeah.
人总有一天都要面对过去
I guess you gotta face your demons sometime.
收到  看到你了
Copy, Q-06, we've got a visual on Lima, Zulu.
九十秒后抵达
ETA at 90 seconds. Stand by.
打起精神  好戏上场
Look alive, men. Game time.
停
Halt.
上吧
Move in.
你一迟疑就会出人命
You hesitate, people die.
方舟传送中心  美国内华达州婴儿湖
UAC ARK FACILITY PAPOOSE LAKE, NEVADA, USA
我们传送出去前我至少检查了三次
I checked it at least three times before we sent it through.
寇森佛  联合航太公关主任
Sanford Crosby, UAC Public Relations.
-请跟我来  -上面有多少人
- Now follow me, please. - How many people you got up there?
欧都瓦有85名全职员工
UAC employs 85 permanent research staff on Olduvai.
欢迎来到方舟
Welcome to the Ark, gentlemen.
启动分子定位器  启动分子定位器
Initiating molecular mapping drive. Initiating molecular mapping drive.
全体人员请准备好
All personnel, prepare for activation.
离远一点  不然会被吸进去
Keep your distance from the core or you might get sucked in.
你进去过吗
You... You done this before?
只有一次  训练任务
Once. Training mission.
希望你吃得饱饱的
Hope you had a good dinner, Kid.
启动星际座标锁定程式
Inter-planet coordinate lock engaged.
测量距离无误  准备传送
All telemetry verified and transmissions are five-by-five.
我们一过去就封锁电梯
Soon as we get through, I need you to shut down the surface elevator.
进行六小时隔离
Make sure that we get the standard quarantine of six hours.
-启动目标接收器  -准备传送
- Target receiver initialized. - Ready to proceed.
15秒后进行方舟传送
Ark travel, 15 seconds and counting.
五  四
Five, four...
三  二
three, two...
一
one.
欧都瓦方舟传送室  火星
OLDUVAI ARK CHAMBER - MARS
干嘛大老远把我们找来
Why we gotta come all this way?
这儿的警卫搞不定吗
Why can't UAC rent-a-cops take care of this bullshit?
非得这么辛苦吗
Is it always that rough?
相信我  以前更糟
Believe me, it used to be a lot rougher.
方舟传送曾经
There was a time when Ark travel was susceptible to, let's say...
-很不稳定  -他是什么意思
- major turbulence. - What's he mean?
他的下半身被送到别的银河系
He means he went to one galaxy, his ass went to another.
那算是估算错误
Call it a scientific miscalculation.
也许你们不信  不过人都会犯错
Unbelievable as it may seem, UAC does make the odd tiny mistake.
平·马可  叫我小平  跟我来
Marcus Pinzerowsky. You call me Pinky. Follow me.
没受困的员工在哪里
Where are the personnel who aren't locked down in the lab?
中庭
In the atrium.
小平  给我影像
Pinky, put us up.
启动遥控监视系统
Activating remote personnel surveillance.
围过来  我数到三
Circle out men, on my three.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
武器摄影机打开了
Killcams up and running.
这是强制隔离
People, this room is a code red, which means...
没有人能擅自出入
no one gets in without our permission.
一定要严密把关
It stays ours at all costs.
迈克  留下来守住入口
Mac, stay here with our friend and secure the door.
弟兄们  上吧
Men, on me. Let's move out.
开门
Open the door.
谁把军队找来
Who called in the military?
这是什么鬼地方
Where the fuck are we?
几百万光年以外
Couple million light years from breakfast.
他们几时能离开
When can I start evacuating people out through the Ark?
这是强制隔离  谁也别想离开
We're at Level 5 quarantine, nobody goes anywhere.
美女  这是强制隔离
Ladies, we're under Level 5 quarantine...
你们得脱光光让我搜身
so I'm just gonna have to strip search you girls.
-你想得美  -我是想得很美
- I don't think so. - Hold that thought.
这是强制隔离  我得
We're under Level 5 quarantine, so I'm just gonna have...
-搜身  -色鬼
- to strip... - Portman!
队长  这是珊曼莎葛姆博士
Sergeant, this is Dr. Samantha Grimm, the UAC science officer...
她负责取回实验室的资料
assigned to retrieve data from the lab.
-队长  -葛博士
- Sergeant. - Dr. Grimm.
-你好  约翰  -你好  珊曼莎
- Hello, John. - Hello, Samantha.
你好啊  珊曼莎
Hello, Samantha!
这是军事行动
Sarge, this operation is a code red.
她不能跟来
We really don't have room for passengers.
我奉命取回三个部门的资料
Excuse me, but I have orders to retrieve data from three servers:
人类学  考古学和基因工程部
Anthropology, Forensic Archeology, and Genetics.
我们来执行军事任务
This is a military operation, Doctor.
不是来拿回你的科学作业
We're really not here to retrieve your science homework.
你问你的指挥官命令是什么
Look, I got an idea. Why don't you ask your CO what your orders are?
解除危机  保护人员
To contain and neutralize the threat, protect the civilians...
取回重要资料
and retrieve UAC property.
好了没  我有工作要做
We finally done here? Because I've got a job to do.
-请跟我来  -是你自己要来的
- If you'll follow me? - You chose this, Reaper.
-这会是麻烦吗  -不会  长官
- Is this gonna spoil my day? - No, sir.
你不是被这辣妹
Tell me you didn't let a fine-looking piece of ass...
-甩掉吧  -她是我姊妹
- like that get away from you. - She's my sister.
-真的假的  -别再这么傻
- No shit? - Don't do this again, man.
哪有
Do what?
柯博士的实验室有三个部门
There's three sections to Carmack's lab complex.
考古学  基因工程和武器研究
Archeology, Genetics, and Weapons Research.
-你们在这里测试武器  -火星上没有生物
- You test weapons up here? - Well, it's a dead planet.
难道你宁愿在地球测试武器
You want that tested here, where it's safe, or in your own backyard?
我们负责进行考古研究
We're primarily an archeological operation.
另一个部门负责测试武器
Weapons Research is in its own separate facility.
那跟柯博士的研究无关
It has nothing to do with Dr. Carmack's work.
多少人被困在实验室
How many inside when the lab shut down?
柯博士的六人研究小组
Only Dr. Carmack's team. That's six people.
实验室有一具电话
In one of the carbon dating labs, there was an internal phone...
没挂断
left off the hook.
有没有录到什么
Did you get any information from it?
开门
Open the door.
色鬼和牧师打头阵
Portman, Goat, lead on.
镁  铬  铅  一切正常
Magnesium, chromium, lead. It's all normal.
安全
All clear.
小平  给我立面图
Pinky, give us a schematic.
正在上传
Uploading to you now.
柯博士的实验室是独立单位
Carmack's lab is isolated from the rest of the facility.
D4气压闸门
气压闸门是唯一的出入口
The airlock is the only way in or out.
方舟传送室-研究办公室  武器研究室-中庭-基因工程部
牧师和色鬼:基因工程部
Goat, Portman: Genetics.
菜鸟和黑霸  柯博士办公室
Kid, Destroyer: Carmack's office, where he sent the mayday from.
死神  保护葛博士安全
Reaper, keep Dr. Grimm here safe on her salvage op.
我和公爵去检查所有的设备
Duke and I'll take the weapons lab, make sure all the hardware's secure.
大伙儿小心点
Be safe, gentlemen.
-色鬼和牧师开路  -是
- Portman, Goat, on you. - It's on.
-左侧安全  -右侧安全
- Clear left. - Clear right.
我打赌一定是离职员工抓狂
$5 says this shit ain't nothing but a disgruntled employee with a gun.
检查过的房间画上记号  上吧
Fluorescent markings as rooms are cleared. Go.
他们出动了
They're on the move.
你不像是叫迈克的
You don't look like a "Mac."
内藤克彦
Katsuhiko Kumanosuke Takaashi.
好吧  迈克
So, Mac.
基因工程研究
搞什么鬼
What the fuck!
小平  你看到吗
Pinky, you getting this?
天啊
Jesus.
酷毙了
Very cool.
安全
Cleared.
人都跑哪儿去了
Where the hell is everybody?
嘿
Hey.
关门
Lock in.
安全了
It's clear.
你需要多少时间
How much time you gonna need?
最多半小时
Thirty minutes, tops.
牧师  色鬼
Goat, Portman.
北侧有另一道门
There's another room to the north.
在基因工程部后面
Past Genetics.
收到
Copy that.
-这是什么鬼地方  -你没蹲过苦窑吗
- What the hell is that? - You never did time, Portman?
什么
What?
-这是禁闭室  -屁啦
- This is a holding cell. - Bullshit.
你怎么知道
What makes you think that?
你摸摸看
Touch it.
-墙壁都通了电  -大烂人
- 'Cause the walls are electrified. - You asshole!
这些武器就这样随便乱放
Jeez. They leave shit like this lying around?
被锁起来的一定更猛
I'd hate to see what they lock up.
生化能量枪
"BFG."
队长  他姊妹是怎样
Hey, Sarge, what's the deal with the sister?
死神的父母是第一批考古学家
Reaper's parents led the first team of archeologists to Olduvai.
他小时候他们就死于意外
They died in some accident when he was a kid.
先进武器
她继承父母的工作  他没有
She followed in their footsteps, and he didn't.
我是问她是不是单身啦
No, what I meant was, is she single?
请提供DNA样本
Please provide DNA verification.
不准进入
Access denied.
所有人员回报
All units report contact.
该死  所有人员回报
God damn it, all units report contact.
它在动
It was moving.
队长  搞错了
Friendly fire, Sarge. Wasting ghosts.
收到
Roger that. Funny, Duke.
他们叫你死神
So, "Reaper?" As in "Grim?"
他们是老粗  不是老师
They're Marines, Sam, not poets.
我的天
Holy shit!
这是露西
Oh, yeah, meet Lucy.
这是我兄弟
Lucy, this is my brother, John...
他也来自过去
another creature from the long lost past.
-你们找到人类遗骸  -类人动物
- You found human remains? - Humanoid.
露西是第一个重大发现
Lucy and her child were our first major find.
每天都挖掘更多遗骸
We're bringing out more every day.
-你们重新开始挖掘  -我应该告诉你
- You re-opened the dig? - I know I should have told you.
但生日卡片
I didn't figure it was the sort of thing...
写不了这么多
I could jot down on a yearly birthday card.
-挖掘工作很安全  -屁啦
- It's been stabilized. - Bullshit.
你怕危险就应该坐办公室
You wanna talk about safe? Like you took a desk job?
我是考古学家  哪儿都得去
I'm a forensic archeologist, John. I'll go where the work is.
这是唯一的原因
Is that the only reason you're up here?
你想知道原因
You wanna know why I'm up here?
我给你看  跟我来
I'll show you. Come here.
这是露西的染色体图像
This is Lucy's chromosome profile. Notice anything?
我学的遗传学都还给老师了
My molecular genetics is a little rusty.
爸爸教我们要注意什么
What's the first thing Dad taught us to look for?
她有24对染色体
She's got 24 pairs of chromosomes.
-人类只有23对  -多出来那一对有什么作用
- Humans only have 23. - But what does the extra pair do?
让她变成超人
Makes her superhuman.
她变得超强壮
The extra pair makes her super strong...
超聪明
super fit, super intelligent.
细胞分裂速度比人类快五十倍
Her cells divide 50 times faster...
伤口几乎能立刻愈合
meaning she heals almost instantly.
化石证明他们克服疾病
The fossil record indicates these people had conquered disease.
没有遗传病  病毒或癌症
We found no genetic disorders, no viruses, no cancers.
他们天生就比较优越
So what, they were just naturally superior?
不  不是天生的
No. Not naturally.
最早发现的只有23对染色体
See, the earliest remains we found only had 23.
第24对应该是合成染色体
We suspect this extra chromosome may be synthetic.
生物工程
Bioengineered?
你这大兵懂得还不少
That's a long word for a Marine.
你选择
Does it ever bother you...
看狙击镜不是显微镜
you could've spent your life looking in a microscope...
不会良心不安吗
instead of a sniper scope?
他们是超人怎么会死呢
If they were so smart, how come they're so dead?
我们不知道
We don't know.
也许只是时间作祟
Maybe they just went with time.
母亲不会怕小孩受时间伤害
You don't shield a baby from time.
前方有动静
We got movement up ahead.
留在这里  把门锁好
You stay here, okay? Lock the door.
这道门被撞穿
Fucking door has been ripped open.
柯博士办公室有东西
There's something in Carmack's office.
那里
There!
发现目标
Contact!
快速向东移动
Moving east through Carmack's office! Fast!
确认目标  从南廊冲过来
Confirmed contact. Moving fast, over south corridor.
停火
Hold your fire!
马上放下武器
If you have a weapon, drop it.
别乱来
Don't move.
-珊  我叫你留在那里  -约翰  他认识我
- Sam, I told you to stay... - But he knows me, John.
柯博士  是我  珊曼莎
Dr. Carmack, it's me. Samantha.
其他人呢
Where are the others? Where are they?
史帝夫和希拉蕊呢
Steve, Hillary...
我不会伤害你
I'm not gonna hurt you.
天啊
Jesus Christ!
-该死  -快拿医药包
- Oh, damn. - Get a med kit.
这下可好
Nice.
我不会伤害你
I'm not gonna hurt you.
陪葛博士到医疗室
Duke, get him to the infirmary with Dr. Grimm.
你们两个守住门口
Portman, Kid, go to the airlock and dig in.
我们会把敌人赶过去
Anything trying to get away from us will get driven straight to you.
我要找到这只手的主人
Now let's see if we can find the body that goes with that arm.
超恶烂的
It's messed up, huh?
柯博士这种人
Guy like Carmack...
一向很理性
who's trained to put logic before emotion...
现在却疯狂到
he's so freaked, huh...
把自己耳朵扯掉
he tears off his own ear?
我告诉你
I tell you, man.
这种鸟事会让你抓狂
It's shit like that that gets under your skin.
你有没有
Do you...
-你有没有那玩意  -有没有什么
- Do you have any? - Do I have any?
什么玩意
What?
你知道嘛
You know.
我有点被吓到  得专心一点
I'm just a little shook up. I need something to get my focus, man.
让我冷静下来
My game face.
该死的上帝
God damn it!
我不该诅咒上帝
I took His name in vain.
哇
Shit.
上帝真的存在
There is a God.
小姐
Ma'am.
小姐  对不起
Excuse me, ma'am.
痛苦
队长
Sarge...
我想我找到那只手的主人了
I think we found the rest of that arm.
不
No, no.
-不  我才不穿过奈米墙  -你一定要
- No, no, I don't do nanowalls. - Yes, you do.
扶住他  在这里等
You got him? Wait here.
真是的
Shit.
二  三
Two, three.
你没事吧
You okay?
-找到其他人吗  -还没有
- Did they find the others? - Not yet.
我先生跟他们一起
My husband is with them.
史帝夫一定没事
I'm sure Steve is fine.
柯博士  我替你量血压
Dr. Carmack, I'm going to take your blood pressure.
-嘿  -没关系
- Hey... - It's okay, it's okay.
-我感觉到它  -发生什么事
- I can feel it. - What happened in there?
把它弄出去  把它弄出去
Shut it down. Shut it down.
把它弄出去
Shut it down.
它在里面
It's inside.
基因工程部有动静  我们要回去
We heard something in Genetics. We're re-entering.
收到了
That's affirmative, Reaper.
看来我们错过一场派对
Looks like we missed the party.
刚刚才来过
We were just here.
那些动物怎么了
What happened to all the animals?
先生  我们是来救你的
Sir, RRTS. We're here to help.
你没事吧
Sir, are you okay?
好吧
Okay.
不  放下来
No, no, no. Sir, put it down.
快报告
Contact report.
该死
Damn it.
找到另一名科学家
We found another one of the scientists.
事情真的很诡异
Some weird shit going on here, Sarge.
-他是谁  -欧森博士
- Can you ID him? - We got a Dr. Olsen.
他像柯博士一样攻击我们
He rushed us. Crazy. Just like Carmack.
-他死了吗  -死透了
- Is he dead? - Yeah, very.
-要把他装进尸袋吗  -不要
- Should we bag him and tag him? - Negative.
继续搜索
Continue your search.
队长
Sarge?
-那是什么  -猴子
- What was that? - A monkey.
一只臭猴子
Some kind of monkey.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
他的血液里有怪东西
There's something in his blood.
他发生什么事
What's happening to him?
-快走  快走  -看到他了
- Move, move, move. - I got him.
-安全  -快走
- Clear! - Go, go, go.
-什么状况  -我们在追一个东西
- Reaper, what have you got? - We're chasing something.
-什么"东西"  -很大的东西  不是人类
- What do you mean, something? - Something big, not human.
该死  告诉我你看到什么
God damn it! Give me a confirmation on what you see.
-死神  -它钻进下水道
- Reaper. - It's in the sewer.
全体队员赶到东南方走廊
All units, all units. Southeast corridor near the med lab.
这下真的要吃屎了
And I thought "being in the shit" was a figure of speech.
快给我下去
Get in the goddamn hole, Portman.
我来接手  你走吧
I can handle things here. You should go.
-我不走  -史帝夫不会有事
- I want to stay. - Steve is gonna be okay.
有最顶尖的军人在找他
The guys looking for him are the best.
快去陪你女儿吧
Go on, go on. Be with your daughter.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这是怎么回事
What's going on?
血型不符
"血型不符"  大事不妙  对吧
"No blood match." Can't be good, right?
不可思议
This is crazy.
我的天
Oh, my God!
前方的隧道
Tunnel ahead is the main junction.
会回到实验室
It leads back under the lab complex.
黑霸  守住出口
Destroyer, cover the exit.
我们找到
We got a Dr. Willits.
史帝夫魏利博士
Steve Willits.
走吧
Move out.
"保持清醒  保持警戒"
"Be sober, be vigilant...
"你的敌人魔鬼"
"because your adversary, the devil...
"随时会吞噬你"
"walketh about seeking whom he may devour."
你好会安慰人
That's real comforting, Goat.
我真放心
That ain't freaking me out at all.
-色鬼  -搞什么
- Portman! - What the fuck?
快
Go, go.
-他被扯下去  -快点
- Wait! Somebody's down there. - Come on.
快抓住他的手
Grab an arm.
-这家伙好重  -撑住
- Goddamn son of a bitch is heavy! - Hang on.
他被扯下去了
Quick, he's slipping back.
He's slipping.
该死
Shit.
发生什么事
Portman, what the hell happened?
我掉进一个坑
I fell in the damn hole.
不会吧
Shit.
大家跟好  走路小心
Everybody, on me. Watch your goddamn footing.
快走
Move.
真是的
Shit.
牧师  向前
Goat, straight ahead.
色鬼  你跟我
Portman, you're with me.
约翰  带菜鸟往右
John, take The Kid and go to the right.
该死
Shit!
你爸妈都挂了  对吧
You lost your folks, right?
闭嘴
Shut up.
真巧  我也没有爹娘
Small world. I mean, I lost my parents, too.
有一天醒来他们就落跑了
Yeah, I mean, I woke up one morning and everything was gone.
丢下我一个人
I mean, the only thing left was me.
他们宁愿要电视机也不要我
They wanted the TV more than they wanted me.
你一开口  就会暴露位置
Every time you open your mouth, you give away our position.
等一下
Wait a minute.
你的瞳孔放大
Your pupils are dilated.
-你嗑了药  -什么
- Are you high? - What?
-没啦  我是生病才吃药  -我才不管
- No, I got this condition... - I don't give a damn.
你敢再嗑药我就轰掉你脑袋
You take one more shot of that shit and I'll blow holes in you.
明白了吗
Are we clear?
明白了
Okay.
趴下来
Get down.
对不起  我只是
I'm sorry, look, I just needed a little...
趴下来
Get down!
牧师  有东西朝你那儿去
Goat, I think there's something coming up on you.
可恶
This isn't happening.
我的灯灭了
My light is down.
什么都看不见
I don't see anything.
别轻举妄动  我马上赶来
Don't move. I'm on my way.
小平
Pinky.
你看到什么
Can you see anything?
什么也没看到
No. Nothing.
魏博士
Dr. Willits?
回报
Report in.
牧师
Goat!
说出你的位置
Goat, what's your position?
你在哪里
Goat, where are you?
快回报
Goat, speak to me.
该死  报告状况
God damn it, Reaper, report to me.
去死吧
You're dead.
快回报
Report contact.
弟兄受伤
Man down.
Man down!
大家回到方舟
Everyone, get to the Ark now!
快到隔离区
Hunegs, report to the quarantine zone.
带大家到方舟传送室
Evacuate the entire facility. Get everyone to the Ark now.
-怎么回事  -快带他们去
- What's going on? - Get to the goddamn Ark.
快走吧
Let's go. Come on.
紧急状况
We have an emergency. Come on.
快到方舟传送室
Everybody to the Ark.
发生什么事
What happened?
他才刚提到魔鬼
He was talking about devils.
魔鬼
Devils?
什么正与邪
All his Bible shit. Angels. Good and evil.
-天使和魔鬼  -把他的防弹背心脱掉
- Devils among us. - Let's get this vest off him.
气道通畅
Now he's clear.
加油
Come on.
脉搏微弱  把点滴给我
Got a weak pulse. Portman, get me a line in here.
振作点
Come on, man.
菜鸟  按住伤口
Kid, keep pressure on that wound.
-脉搏如何  -快要没了
- How's the pulse? - I'm losing him.
给我一针肾上腺素
Sam, give me a shot of adrenaline.
-没有脉搏  -我要进行电击
- We lost the pulse. - Okay, let's defib.
加油
Come on, man.
让开
Clear!
柯博士在哪里
Where the hell's Carmack?
他不见了
He disappeared.
那是什么意思
What do you mean, he disappeared?
他消失不见了
He's gone. He disappeared.
-失去脉搏  -该死
- I've lost the pulse. - Shit.
好
Okay.
我要电击  让开
Gonna defib. Clear!
-快点  -快点
- Come on. - Come on.
-没有反应  -他就快死了
- No response. - We're losing him.
快给我肾上腺素
Sam, give me that adrenaline.
加油  兄弟
Come on, you son of a bitch.
再一次  让开
Okay, going again. Clear!
他死了
He's gone.
博士  这到底是怎么回事
Doctor, you are going to tell me what the fuck is going on up here.
-什么  -过来
- What? - Come here.
给我过来
Come here!
这是什么
This is "what."
天啊
God.
你有挖掘到这种东西吗
Have you found anything like this on your archeological digs?
没有
No.
有没有可能来自地面
Is there any way this thing came from the outside, from the surface?
火星上没有生物
The planet is completely dead.
它一定来自哪里
It came from somewhere, lady.
闭嘴
Portman, shut up!
火星表面大气层无法维生
The atmosphere on the surface can't support life.
或许它不需要空气
Maybe it doesn't need air.
它搞不好来自别的星球
It could have come from another planet or something.
你是说外星人
What? Like an alien?
-看看这恶烂玩意  -色鬼
- Look at that thing! - Portman!
给我乖乖闭嘴
You need to shut the fuck up!
我们不是看到这玩意
That's not what we saw.
这不是我们看到的那一个
That's not what Goat and I shot at in Genetics.
你是说还有更多
You telling me there's more of these fucking things?
地面的出口在哪里
Where are your surface entry points?
北廊有气压闸门
There's a pressure door at the end of the north corridor.
黑霸  菜鸟  色鬼  你们马上带他们去  到了就回报
Destroyer, Kid, Portman, get there on the double. Give me an update.
-收到  -绝对不能让
- Yes, sir. - Whatever this thing is...
这玩意回到地球
it cannot get back through the Ark.
迈克  给小平一枚手榴弹
Mac, I want you to arm Pinky with a weapon...
封锁方舟传送门
with some ST grenades, and seal the Ark door.
还有另一道门
There's one other door.
哪里
Where?
通往考古遗址的入口
The entrance to the archeological dig.
启动方舟传送门
Ark portal activation in progress.
别让任何东西进入方舟
Don't let anything through the Ark.
你不能丢下我
Hey, wait. Wait a minute. You can't leave me here.
我又不是军人
I'm not a soldier.
你去死吧
Why don't you go fuck yourself?
这太扯了
It's bullshit.
你应该保护我
You're supposed to protect me.
方舟传送门关闭
Ark secure.
所有人员准备撤离
Remaining personnel, ready for evacuation.
该死
Shit.
公爵
Duke.
帮我拉开
Hold this open.
别畏畏缩缩的
Don't be a wuss.
你跟死神处得不好
Little tension between you and Reaper?
我们的目标不同
We just went our separate ways.
他那么有天份  为什么要放弃一切加入雷霆小队
Why does a talented student throw it all away and join RRTS?
他以前是什么样子
So, what was he like before?
-谁  约翰吗  -对
- Who, John? - Yeah.
感情丰富  敏锐
Empathetic, sensitive.
我很难想像他是这种人
It's kind of hard for me to imagine Reaper as sensitive.
早在"伏地挺身50下  呜啊"  之前我就了解他了
I knew Reaper before all the "drop down and give me 50, woo-ha" stuff.
是吗
Yeah?
-是"呼啊"  -"呼啊"
- Well, it's, "Hoo-ha." - "Hoo-ha."
对
Yeah.
你的家人呢
Do you have a family?
我有黑霸  我们从小一起长大
I have Destroyer. You know, we grew up together.
你私底下一定是宽大善良的吧
You know, Duke, I bet secretly you have a big heart.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
我私底下宽大的东西还不少喔
And that's not the only secret big thing I got.
大不如前了哦
Little rusty, huh?
你无法想像
Oh, lady, you have no idea.
现在跟我做爱才是你该做的事
Right now, having sex with me is practically your civic duty.
我需要一把骨锯
I need a power bone saw.
骨锯
A power bone saw?
你是我的梦中情人
Girl, I've been waiting on you my whole life.
手术室里有
There's one in the procedure room.
穿过奈米墙  在走廊尽头的左手边
Down the corridor, on the left, through the nanowall.
穿过奈米墙
Through the nanowall?
好吧  我去拿
All right, I got it. It's cool.
因为你很漂亮  为了你我去拿
For you I got it, 'cause you're pretty.
很好
Cool.
我可不会为男人这么做
I wouldn't do it for a dude, you know.
去吧
Off you go.
我们要从气压闸门回去
We're going back in through the airlock.
不呼叫支援吗
We're not calling in backup?
方舟传送门关闭
The Ark is sealed.
火星怪物完全消灭才能打开
Nothing gets back until everything on this planet is dead.
我们要赶尽杀绝
We're going in hot.
你是说真的吗
You're serious.
把枪拿起来
Pick up your weapon, Portman.
快点行动
Come on, Portman, move out.
牧师被咬得稀巴烂
Didn't y'all see how that thing greased Goat?
我们连那是什么都不知道
We don't know what we're dealing with here.
呼叫支援是例行程序
It's SOP to call in reinforcements when a situation...
我们
We are...
就是支援
the reinforcements.
给我
Now, you shoulder...
把枪拿起来
your fucking weapon, soldier.
所有员工都已回到地球
All UAC personnel evacuated to Earth.
公爵
Duke?
Duke!
别怕  只是跳电
Hey, hey, hey. It's just a power shortage.
没事吧
You okay?
你要的骨锯
Here's your bone saw.
-你们谁比较大  -什么
- So, which of you is the oldest? - What?
我  我大他两分钟
Oh, me. By two minutes.
哇塞  你们是双胞胎
Twins? Shit.  Identical, right?
回去实验室
Sam, get back in the lab.
该死
Shit.
去死吧
Motherfucker!
快关门
Close it!
所以我才不敢进奈米墙
And that's why I don't do nanowalls.
我们进入考古遗址
Pinky, we're entering the archeological dig.
守住出口
Secure the exit.
-珊  -我来了
- Sam. - I'm coming.
我饿了  来吃东西吧
I'm hungry. Let's eat.
过来看
Come on. Come on.
-小心点  -别太靠近了
Careful now. Not too close, John.
快点
Go, go, go.
慢一点
Slow down.
再来一次
Go around. Go around again.
不  妈
No! Mommy!
就是在这儿发生
Is this where it happened?
找到门了吗
Did you find the door?
约翰
John?
克雷
Clay.
舒曼
Thurman.
看看他们
Look at them.
他们不是阻止什么进来
They weren't trying to stop something from getting in.
有什么不让他们出去
Something stopped them from getting out.
迈克  待命
Mac, stand by.
-黑霸  回报  -到达北闸门
- Destroyer, report. - We've reached the north airlock.
一切安全
It's secure.
记录显示26小时内无人进出
Console indicates nothing's come in or out for 26 hours.
迈克
Mac?
Mac.
迈克  收到吗
Mac, Mac, you copy?
快回答  迈克
Talk to me. Talk to me, Mac.
可恶
Shit.
老天爷
Jesus Christ.
看到目标  我们在追赶  对方动作很快
We're in pursuit. Moving fast out of the dig.
向右
It's getting away.
你看到什么
Pinky, what do you see?
那怪物超大
It's big. Very big.
动作超快  它回去实验室
Moving fast, back towards the lab complex.
安全
Clear.
它回到实验室
It's back in the lab.
安全
Clear!
Clear.
它超快的
Damn, it's fast.
全面防卫
All around defense, men.
逮到它了吗
Did you get it?
-小平  -什么事
- Pinky. - Yes, Sarge?
它想闯进去就用手榴弹
Anything gets through that door, use an ST grenade.
不能让它回到地球
It cannot get back to Earth.
这样会把方舟给炸掉
He pops an ST in there, he's gonna blow the Ark.
死神和菜鸟
Reaper, Kid, pairs, cover formation.
展开搜索  快去
Sweep the corridors. Go.
黑霸和色鬼留下来  关闭气压闸门
Destroyer, you and Portman stay here. Shut the airlock.
严加戒备
Maintain a perimeter.
方舟被炸掉我们怎么回去
He blows the Ark, how the hell are we supposed to get the fuck home?
给我把门关起来
Portman, shut the fucking door.
你要去哪里
Where you going?
军火库
I'm going to the armory.
我需要更猛的武器
I think we're gonna need something with a little bit more kick.
天啊
Jesus.
你看过这玩意吗
You see anything like it before?
心脏
Heart.
肝脏
Liver.
肾脏
Kidneys.
狗有肾脏
Dogs got kidneys, right?
猪也有肾脏
Pigs got kidneys.
它的盲肠被割除
It's had its appendix removed.
它是人类
It's human.
搞什么
What the fuck?
牧师知道自己变成怪物
Goat knew he was turning.
这怪物没吃掉魏博士
This thing didn't butcher Willits.
它就是魏博士
It is Willits.
什么
What?
这太扯了
This is bullshit, man.
我当兵是为国家打仗
I enlisted to serve my country, not get greased protecting some...
不是替私人公司送掉小命
corporation's goddamn science project.
我要去撇条
I gotta take a dump.
现在吗
What? Now?
你要我拉在裤子里吗
Unless you want me shitting my pants right here.
先进武器
请提供DNA样本
Please provide DNA verification.
泰碧翠  欢迎  准许进入
Welcome, Patricia Tallman. Access granted.
好大的一把枪
Big fucking gun.
哇靠
Shit.
你的摄影机只拍到地板墙壁
Portman, I got floor and wall on your gun cam.
我在撇条啦  臭跛脚
I'm taking a shit, you fucking gimp.
你这大烂人去死吧
Fuck you, Portman, you piece of shit.
色鬼失联  黑霸面对墙壁
Lost Portman on comm and all I've got on Destroyer is a wall.
色鬼  回答
Portman, come in.
黑霸
Destroyer.
回答
Come in.
这是雷霆小队队员
This is Corporal Dean Portman...
我在欧都瓦执行任务
with RRTS 6 Special Ops on Olduvai, 0310 hours.
我们遭到敌人攻击
We have encountered hostile activity.
重覆  请求立刻派出支援
I repeat, require immediate RRTS reinforcements.
黑霸  色鬼  你们在哪里
Destroyer, Portman, where the hell are you?
该死
Shit.
我的天啊
Oh, God! Jesus!
-你看到色鬼吗  -没有
- Pinky, you got Portman? - No.
我的妈呀
Holy shit.
他死了
He's gone.
黑霸
Destroyer?
色鬼也死了
And Portman.
出了什么事
What the fuck happened, man?
我来扶他
I got him, I got him.
有我在  没事了
I got you, man.
你出了什么事
What's up, man?
发生什么事
What the hell is this?
玻璃上的血是谁的
And whose goddamn blood is on that window?
牧师的
Goat's.
他自杀了
He killed himself.
他死了怎么能自杀
What do you mean, he killed himself? He was already dead.
真的
It's true.
是牧师
It's Goat.
他变成怪物  所以才自杀
He was changing into one of these motherfuckers and he killed himself.
我们发现两名科学家
We found two more scientists at the dig.
舒曼和戴眼镜的秃头佬
Thurman and a balding guy with glasses.
克雷博士
Dr. Clay.
他们的脖子
Did you check their necks?
有没有伤口
Were there open wounds on their necks?
我们在打仗  没时间验尸
We were conducting a firefight, not an autopsy.
我们来找六名科学家  其中四名死了
We came up here to find six scientists. Four are known dead...
魏博士一定也挂了
and Dr. Willits is probably KIA somewhere down in that sewer.
现在只缺柯博士
The only one missing is Dr. Carmack.
他有没有出现
Has Dr. Carmack showed up yet?
他是有出现
Oh, he's shown up all right.
看看它的左耳
Look at the left ear.
我的天
Son of a bitch.
另一个是史帝夫
I think this other one is Steve Willits.
我要进行DNA比对
I'm going to run the DNA, check it against his med records.
你们到底在做什么
What are you people working on up here?
分析化石和古物
We're analyzing bones, artifacts.
并没有进行秘密实验
We're not doing anything like this.
那这是怎么回事
Then what the fuck is that?
这一定是基因突变  环境或病毒造成的
It must be a genetic mutation, something environmental or viral.
我不知道
I don't know.
也许可以治好
It may even be reversible.
治不好的
It's irreversible.
不一定
Not necessarily.
柯博士这样子
Dr. Carmack's condition...
绝对好不了
is irreversible...
柯博士变成怪物
because Carmack's condition is that...
所以要死
he's dead.
菜鸟  跟公爵
Kid, you and Duke...
到考古遗址  确定其他的科学家
get back to the dig and you make sure those other dead scientists...
都死透了
are really dead.
我失去
I've lost...
四名弟兄
four soldiers.
你们到底在做什么实验
What are you people experimenting with up here?
我不想再问一遍
I'm not gonna ask you again.
我说过  这是考古研究中心
I told you, it's an archeological research center.
你认为我在骗你吗
Do you think I'm lying to you? Is that what you're saying?
我在隐瞒什么吗
You think I'm hiding something?
我说的是实话
I'm telling the truth.
你在下载什么
What were you downloading?
保护什么
What were you sent to protect?
研究资料
The research data.
什么研究资料
Research into what?
实验对像被注射药剂
Subject was injected with study agent at 00:03.
心率加快是焦虑造成的
Vitals normal, elevated heart rate attributable to subject anxiety.
成功注入实验对像体内
C- 24 successfully grafted to subject's marker cells at 00:09.
他在进行基因突变的实验
He reconstructed chromosome mutation on a human subject.
我们不打算做人体实验
We were never gonna do human studies.
这是怎么回事
What the hell are we looking at?
创世纪  第一章
Genesis, Chapter 1.
实验对像被移往观察室
Subject moved to protected observation area at 00:17.
实验对像:史寇特
Subject: Curtis Stahl.
罪行:多重谋杀
Crime: Multiple murder.
判决:死刑
Status: Condemned to execution.
第24对染色体
Chromosome 24.
天啊
Oh, my God.
注射后49分钟
49 minutes after injection, genetic mutations...
对像的身体出现基因变化
began to visually manifest on subject's extremities.
你就是来拿这些
This is what you're here to protect.
这没有道理
It doesn't make any sense.
你相信他们  他们欺骗你
You trusted them. They lied to you.
你被利用了
They used you, Sam.
如果他成功改造人类
If he perfected xenogenesis...
你还不明白吗
Christ, don't you get it?
这地方一直都是地狱
It's this place. It's hell. It always was.
我要结束这一切
This shit ends here.
你想干嘛
What are you doing?
毁了这些碟片
We need to destroy these discs.
这是联合航太财产
That's UAC property.
去它的  这玩意有害
Fuck UAC, we take this back, they'll just...
我们要把资料带回去
We take the data back.
难道你没看到吗
Sarge, do you not see what's going on here?
我什么也没看到
I didn't see shit.
我拿了钱就要办事
And I ain't paid to see shit.
你和我都要奉命行事
I have my orders. And so do you.
就是这些吗
Is this everything?
我问你就是这些吗
I said, is this everything?
-我还要下载三个碟片  -那就快下载
- I have three more to download. - Then do it.
队长
Sarge?
有麻烦
We got a problem.
有一个死人不见了
One dead scientist is missing.
快点
Now.
你要把她丢在这儿
You just wanna leave her here?
她有工作要做
She's got a job to do.
这是对讲机  有事就呼叫我
Look, this is Portman's comm. You call if you need help, okay?
你不会有事吧
You gonna be all right?
我不会有事
I'll be fine.
好吧  待会见
Okay. I'll see you soon.
小平  你在吗
Pinky, are you there? Pinky.
有东西向方舟冲过来
Sarge? Something is cutting through the Ark door.
你看到它吗
You have a visual?
我看得一清二楚
Oh, I got a visual all right.
别让它闯进去
Don't let it get to the Ark!
-快用手榴弹  -四
- Pinky, use the grenade! - Four.
-快丢手榴弹  -三  二
- Use the goddamn grenade! - Three, two.
-快丢  -一
- Throw it! - One.
小平那胆小鬼落跑了
Pinky's gone. That fucker ran.
该死
Shit.
它闯到地球了
It got through.
怎么回事
What the hell is that?
系统重新开机
System reboot.
五分钟后重新开启
Time required to begin renewed operation: Five minutes.
隔离区遭侵入
Quarantine cordon is breached.
任务改变
This mission is no longer containment.
带着武器弹药  我们要回去
Get all the weapons and ammo you can. We're going through.
快点
Move!
珊  回答
Sam, come in. Over.
珊  收到吗  快回答
Sam, do you read me? Over. Come in!
她没有回应
She's not answering.
传送门
Time required to begin renewed operation...
4分45秒后开启
four minutes and 45 seconds.
你只有3分钟
You got three.
珊  快回答
Sam! Come in, Sam!
珊
Sam!
你怎么不回答  我们得快走
Sam, why didn't you answer your comm? We gotta go now!
它为什么只咬牧师不咬黑霸
Why did they take Goat and not Destroyer?
只咬柯博士不咬舒曼
Why Carmack and not Dr. Thurman?
-什么  -露西并没有
- What? - Lucy had the 24th chromosome...
变成怪物
but she wasn't a monster.
她在保护小孩  不是吃掉他
She died protecting her child, not devouring it.
她变成超人
Why did the same chromosome that made her superhuman...
柯博士却变成怪物
turn Stahl into a monster?
-走吧  -等我一分钟
- Let's go. - Just give me a minute.
-不能等了  -等我十秒钟
- We don't have a minute. - Then give me 10 seconds.
这是它的舌头
This is its tongue.
这是色鬼的脑浆
This is brain matter from Portman.
这是黑霸的脑浆
This is from Destroyer.
它在挑选
It's choosing, John.
感染的对像
It's choosing who to infect.
它怎么挑选对像
It's choosing? How is it choosing?
暴力和变态狂有特定基因标记
There are genetic markers for psychotic and violent behavior.
也许它能辨识他们的脑波
It could be a specific neurotransmitter...
或神经节
it's picking up on, a ganglion.
他们的DNA含有
Latching onto numbers in the DNA code linked to...
什么  邪恶特质
Linked to what? Evil?
人类的基因体有一成未被开发
Ten percent of the human genome is still unmapped.
有人说那是人的灵魂
Some say it's the genetic blueprint for the soul.
也许C24染色体毁了这个文明
Maybe C-24 is what destroyed the population.
他们建造方舟
It would explain why some of them had to build the Ark...
准备重新开始
to escape to a new beginning.
有些人变成超人  其他人则变成怪物
Some it made superhuman. Others, monsters.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
-我们得赶快走  -什么
- We gotta get out of here now. - What?
快点  来吧
Come on, let's go, come on.
不是每个人
The people quarantined on the other side of the Ark...
都受到感染
they won't all be infected!
怎么回事
What's going on?
队长要把他们全杀死  快来
Sarge is going to kill them all. Come on.
这是隔离行动  谁都不准回去
We uphold quarantine. Nothing gets to the elevator back on Earth.
不能让他们回到地面
We can't let them get to the surface.
-只要是活人都格杀勿论  -五
- If it breathes, kill it. - Five...
四  三
four, three...
二  一
two, one.
方舟传送完毕
Ark travel complete.
方舟传送中心  美国内华达州婴儿湖
UAC ARK FACILITY PAPOOSE LAKE, NEVADA, USA
这是雷霆小队队员
This is Corporal Dean Portman...
我在欧都瓦执行任务
with RRTS 6 Special Ops on Olduvai, 0310 hours.
我们遭到敌人攻击
We have encountered hostile activity.
请求立刻派出支援
Require immediate RRTS reinforcements.
是啊
Yeah, no shit.
58分钟后自动封锁会解除
We got 58 minutes before the auto lockdown is lifted.
重新设定成六小时
Reset it for another six hours.
不行  电脑被它们破坏
I can't. It's been disabled.
我们也和地面失联
Same as the topside comm link.
它们会破坏电脑
They're disabling computers now?
他们以前是科学家耶
Yeah, they're rocket scientists, remember?
方舟传送完毕
Ark travel complete.
我的天
Oh, my God.
队长  你在哪里
Sarge, what's your position?
队长  回答  你收到吗
Sarge, come in. Do you copy?
Come in, Sarge. Do you read me? Over.
队长  回答  你收到吗
Sarge, come in, do you copy?
收到了
Loud and clear.
有人没受感染
Look, do not kill everybody. I repeat, do not kill everybody.
不要赶尽杀绝
They're not all infected.
-救救我  求求你  -收到吗
- Help me, help me, please. - Do you copy?
-收到了  -救我
- Copy that. - Help me.
清除这一区后回方舟传送室
Clear the rest of this sector and meet back at the Ark chamber.
-老天爷  你干嘛开枪  -还有谁在里面
- Jesus Christ, what the hell are... - Who the hell's in there?
别光站着  扶我起来
Well, don't just stand there, you dumb son of a bitch. Help me up.
没事
It's okay.
求求你
Please...
救救我们
help us.
你不必赶尽杀绝
You don't have to kill all of them.
有些人没被感染  也不会被感染
I don't think everyone is infected, or even capable of being infected.
我们奉命不择手段解除危机
We have orders to contain this threat by any means necessary.
让没事的人离开
So let's evacuate the uninfected...
再炸掉这地方
and blow this place to hell.
我们奉命保护这地方
And we have orders to protect this facility.
我们没有奉命屠杀无辜百姓
We don't have orders to kill innocent people.
我们必须不择手段
We have to stop anything from getting to the surface...
阻止任何东西
by any means...
侵入地面
necessary.
我找到这个胆小鬼
Found this little chicken shit hiding under a pile of dead bodies.
见到你们真好
Am I glad to see you guys.
那只怪物硬闯进来
That thing cut right through the door.
它太快  来不及丢手榴弹
I tried to use the grenade but it came at me too fast.
它跟过来  杀死每个人
Followed me through the Ark and started to kill everybody.
太可怕了
It was horrible.
他脖子没伤口  没有被感染
There's no wound on his neck. He's clean.
谁被感染
I say who's clean...
由我说了算
and who's not.
不是我的错
I mean, it wasn't my fault.
我又不是军人  你不该丢下我
Hey, I'm not a soldier. You shouldn't have left me...
队长
Sarge.
南侧有一间储藏室
There's a storeroom to the south.
里面有20人
It's got, like, 20 people holed up inside of it.
我们得帮助他们
We gotta do something.
你奉命歼灭所有人
Your orders were to clear that sector.
他们都死了吗
Is it cleared?
没  我叫他们留在那里
No, I told them to stay put.
他们没危险  只是被吓坏
They're okay. They're just scared shitless.
我们要杀光他们
We kill them all.
让上帝决定谁是好人
Let God sort them out.
这是错的
This is wrong.
-我想  -小子  不要想
- I think... - Son, you don't think.
你要奉命行事
That's an order.
这是场战争  大兵
We're in the field, soldier.
如果他们还没被感染
Sarge, if nothing's found them...
你要乖乖
You will obey the direct order...
听指挥官的命令
of your commanding officer.
不
No.
快去
Now.
你去死吧
Go to hell.
-不  -我靠
- No. - Holy shit.
违抗命令的下场就是
Mutinous insurrection is punishable...
死
by death.
-这是他的第一次任务  -这不会是我最后的一次任务
- It was his first mission! - And it's not gonna be my last.
我只需要
I need soldiers.
奉命行事的军人
I don't need anybody else but soldiers.
把枪放下
Drop the weapons.
我警告你
I mean it.
我不想被疯子杀死  快放下
I have no intention of being killed by a madman. Drop the weapons.
我后面有什么  对吧
There's something behind me, isn't there?
跟我来
On me.
去帮珊
Get Sam.
在这里等
Wait here.
你听
Listen.
撤退到奈米墙后面
Withdraw! Withdraw behind the nanowall.
-快点  -我看不到
- Move! - I can't see. I can't see.
快走
Move.
安全
Clear!
靠  奈米墙关不起来
Fuck! The wall's not closing!
我不应该死的
I'm not supposed to die.
走吧
Let's go.
快来吧
Come on.
安全
Clear.
它们几时会闯进来
How long before they get through?
就快了
Not long.
你中弹了
You've been hit.
约翰
Oh, John.
听我说
Listen to me, Sam.
你好冷  你在发抖
You're cold. Shivering.
听好了
It's important.
这是手榴弹
This is an ST grenade.
它们一闯进来
When they come through...
掀开盖子按下开关
you pop the top and hit the button.
振作点  保持清醒
John, stay with me. Stay awake.
约翰  保持清醒
John, stay with me, please.
那是什么
What's that?
-染色体  -不
- It's C-24. It's from Carmack's lab. - No.
-它能救你一命  -不  不行
- It could save you. - No way, forget it.
你会流血致死
You're bleeding to death.
我不要
No way, Sam.
我干过很多坏事
I've done some bad things.
我了解你
I know you.
你不了解我
You don't know me.
你不了解
You don't know.
你是我弟弟  我了解你
You're my brother. I know you.
等等
Wait.
要是我变成怪物
If I should turn into one of those demons.
别犹豫
One through the heart, one through the head...
朝我的心和头开枪
don't you hesitate. Okay?
我不必这么做
I won't need to.
我了解你
I know you.
你是我弟弟
You're my brother.
珊
Sam?
禁止进入
珊
Sam.
约翰
John.
珊
Sam.
封锁
-珊  -你还活着
- Sam. - You're alive.
别出声
Don't talk.
看来我们都熬过来了
Last man standing, Reaper.
她需要治疗
I think she needs medical attention.
-你能爬到电梯吗  -我不确定
- Can you get to the elevator? - I'm not sure.
试试看
Try.
菜鸟找到的生还者呢
Where are the survivors Kid found?
都被我解决掉了
I took care of that problem.
强制隔离就快结束  随时会恢复电力
Quarantine's almost over. Power should be back on any minute.
-你杀死菜鸟  -你我都是冷血杀手
- You killed The Kid. - We're all killers, Reaper.
这是我们的职责
It's what they pay us for.
强制隔离结束  电梯恢复作业
Quarantine complete. Elevators back on line.
一切都结束了
It's finished.
咱们不如到外面透透气
What do you say we go outside and get some fresh air?
-你要向我开枪  -我是这么想
- Are you gonna shoot me? - Yeah, I was thinking about it.
-你剩多少弹药  -半个弹匣  你呢
- What you got left? - Half a clip. You?
我剩下最后一枪
I've got one round.
永远忠诚  混帐东西
Semper fi, motherfucker.
永远效忠海军陆战队
Faithful to the Corps, John.
准备
启动方舟
启动方舟传送门
Ark portal activation in progress.
五
Five...
四  三
four, three...
二  一
two, one.
就像菜鸟说的
Like The Kid said:
"你去死吧"
"Go to hell."
就快到家了
Almost home.